Carlos Ugaz

carlosgub.dev@gmail.com | +51994782277 carlosgub.dev github.com/carlosgub

Career Summary

Carlos is a Bachelor's in System Engineering from the Universidad de Lima, with six years of experience in Android application development using Kotlin and Java programming languages. He is an Android Leader in his current workplace who has led up to three developers and is interested in researching emerging technologies. He has experience in banking, education, e-commerce, and media industries.

Summary of Qualifications

Proficient in:

- Android (6 years)
- Kotlin (4 years)
- Java
- Git

- Design Patterns
- Data Patterns
- Jetpack Compose
- Kotlin coroutines

- Rx Kotlin
- MVVM
- Clean Architecture
- Data Structure

Languages

- Spanish (native C2)
- English (intermediate- B1)

Career History

Globant, Lima, Peru (August. 2022 - Present)

Android Developer Mar. 2023 - Present

Yape

Responsibilities:

- Maintaining and adding new functionalities to the application and developing the new version of the appl.
- Coordination with the development team and the area manager.
- Fix related bugs.

Tools/Technologies: Compose, Coroutines, Kotlin, Koin, MVVM.

Android Developer Aug. 2022 – Dec. 2022

Ticketmaster Responsibilities:

- Maintaining and adding new functionalities to the application, related to the SDK that is integrated into other companies App as NFL, NBA for example.
- Coordination with the development team and the area manager.
- Re-design of screens.
- Fix related bugs.

Tools/Technologies: Coroutines, Kotlin, Java

Rappi, Lima, Peru

Android Developer Tech Lead

Apr. 2021 – Aug. 2022

Responsibilities:

- Implement new functionalities and improvements to the search screens in the application transforming this on 1.5 million dollars per month in revenue.
- Implementation of a modular architecture for the search modules.
- Coordination with the development team and the area manager.
- Re-design of screens.

Tools/Technologies: Kotlin, MVVM, Rx Kotlin

Scotiabank, Lima, Peru

Android Developer Responsibilities:

Jun. 2020 – Apr. 2021

- Development of new features for the Bank's application.
- Implementation of Login with biometrics in the Bank's application.
- Migrate the Java code to Kotlin Language in the modules I had on my own.

Tools/Technologies: Kotlin, Java, MVVM

TiSmart, Lima, Peru

Android Developer for Arisale TiSmart sub-company Responsibilities:

May. 2019 – May. 2020

- Development of the self-service for Ripley and Cruz del Sur, where payment can be made by debit or credit card and a virtual wallet.
- Development, maintenance, and testing of Android mobile applications.
- Management of the deployment of new versions in the Play Store.

Tools/Technologies: Kotlin, MVVM, Koin, Rx Kotlin

Mapsalud SAC, Lima, Peru

Android Developer Responsibilities:

Nov. 2018 – Apr. 2019

- Development, maintenance, and testing of Android mobile applications.
- Management of the deployment of new versions in the Play Store.

Tools/Technologies: Kotlin, MVVM, Dagger

Firefly Digital, Lima, Peru

Android Developer Responsibilities:

Nov. 2018 – Apr. 2019

- Development, maintenance, and testing of the Android mobile application.
- Management of the deployment of new versions in the Play Store.

Tools/Technologies: Kotlin, MVVM, Dagger

Universidad de Lima, Lima, Peru

Android Developer Responsibilities: Feb. 2018 - Nov. 2018

• Development, maintenance, and testing of the Android mobile application of the university.

Tools/Technologies: Java, MVP

Farenet, Lima, Peru

Android Developer Mar. 2017 – Jan. 2018 Responsibilities:

• Development, maintenance, and testing of YOLO: an Android mobile application used for selling drinks and food in some nightclubs in an automated way.

Tools/Technologies: Java, MVP

Education

Universidad de Lima, Lima, Peru 2019

Mar. 2013 – Jun.

BS, Systems Engineering